The ethnic tapestry of the city we all love and call home. I love that.
Next we have Berj Shakarian inducted by Paul Berg. Paul is a 2019 inductee. He
is
delegate for the Czech Cultural Garden and past president of the Cleveland
Cultural Gardens Federation. He is currently also serving as president of
Soho Cleveland and the historic Bohemian National Hall.
It's my real pleasure and privilege to introduce to you my friend and colleague,
Berj Shakarian.
You can all read his cycle as an appropriate. We're getting 90 seconds and we're
way too long to try to list them.
Berj Shakarian cherishes his Armenian heritage, although he was born and grew
up in Bucharest, Romania.
As with many refugee families, the path to safety and success is long and
winding.
Purchasing architects. When asked about his design, you're likely to hear about
the history and the philosophy that influenced the design.
It's never just the design of Spain.
Among the many projects for the city, county and university, he also designed
the Armenian Cultural Garden
and is currently helping the Turkish community design their garden.
Now, for those of you aware of the recent history and attention in that region,
it is absolutely admirable that Mr. Shakarian
would rise above it all for the sake of friendship and mutual understanding of
the model of these spectacular cultural gardens
and share his down below it all. That is Berj.
Berj Shakarian arrived in America on July 4th and there were firewalls.
He and his wife Carol, an American of Hungarian heritage, wed in 1971.
They brought up four children, all of whom now love PhDs. And of course, they
are very proud of him.
Berj, it is my pleasure to present to you the Cleveland International Hall of
Fame.
Thank you Paul Burek. Cheers to Dr. Wai Kuri.
And my sister gratitude to the entire Hall of Fame committee for selecting me
to join such a prestigious company.
I am both honored and humbled for this award.
Also, I want to extend my appreciation for the support of Susieh Adesian,
President of Darwinian Cultural Garden,
Adita Kuzarian and Ted Arslanian. Thank you.
Cleveland has been a journey of discovery for me for almost 60 years.
This town has become a place that I go home and have created a family life with
a lovely, local Hungarian girl.
We met on the old CES WAPA transit while commuting to college.
And are now married for 50 years and as Paul said, we have four very successful
children, each with PhDs.
Thank you, Carol.
As a young man wandering the streets of downtown Cleveland, I came to love the
city passion.
Little did I know that one day I will be responsible for restoring and
repairing the imposing Soldiers and Sailors monument.
Or that I will have a hand in saving the state and Ohio theaters.
I recall walking in the State Theater with a roof collapsing and seeing East of
Java movie poster with Robert Mitchell.
Today, well, it's certainly a success story.
Once again, many thanks for this special honor. Thank you.
[BLANK_AUDIO]